Guide to the Loomis-Wilder Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
American Ephemeris and Nautical Almanac; African Americans -- History -- 1863-1877; Architecture, Domestic -- Designs and plans; Astronomy; Botany -- Florida; Solar eclipses -- 1889; Families; House furnishings; Law; Literature -- History and criticism; Petroleum industry and trade -- West Virginia; Science; Students; Transcendentalism (New England); Women poets; Africa; Boston (Mass.) -- Social life and customs; Fairfax County (Va.); New England -- Description and travel; New York (State) -- Social life and customs; Otsego County (N.Y.); South Africa -- Description and travel; Southern States; United States -- Armed Forces -- African Americans; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; West Indies; Account books; Diaries; Sermons; Astronomers; Clergy; Inventors; Lawyers; Soldiers; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873; Birney, William, 1819-1907; Burritt, Elijah H. (Elijah Hinsdale), 1794-1838; Burroughs, John, 1837-1921; Clark, Alvan Witcombe, 1892-; Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882; Gardner, E. C. (Eugene Clarence), 1836-1915; Gee, John Henry, 1819-1876; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920; Lawrence Scientific School; Loomis, Eben Jenks, 1828-1912; Loomis, Mary Alden Wilder, 1831-1910; Newcomb, Simon, 1835-1909; Shoemaker, William Lukens, 1822-; Stanton, Edwin M. (Edwin McMasters), 1814-1869; Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874; Thoreau, Henry David, 1817-1862; Thoreau, Maria, 1794-1881; Thoreau, Sophia E.; Twiss, Stephen Prince, 1827-; Watson, Sereno, 1826-1892; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892; Wilder, John Augustus, 1834-1870; Winter, William, 1836-1917; Wright, Chauncey, 1830-1875; Barber famliy; Loomis family; Wilder family; United States. Army ( African American troops)
- LOOMIS FAMILY: GENERAL, 1803-(1821-1913)-1968; Series I; 2.25 linear feet (5 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the correspondence, legal and financial papers, diaries, writings and miscellany of Loomis family members over four generations to 1915; together with some biographical and genealogical material about the family to 1968. The papers of Eben J. Loomis are extensive and have been assigned to a separate series (see Series II).
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically under the name of the family member to whom the letter is written, and alphabetically by author. See general note on correspondence in the Introduction to the register.
  Personal and Legal Records is preceded by several folders of biographical and genealogical materials, and material which could not be assigned to any one member of the family. The rest of this sub-series is arranged alphabetically under the name of the family member to whom the material pertains; the folders for each person are in rough chronological order.
  - Correspondence
    - Avery, Susan Look
      - Loomis, Eben J. (8), 1880-1898, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Todd, David Peck and Todd, Mabel Loomis
        General
        See: Todd collections
    - Bagg, Mary S. Loomis
      - B-W, and unidentified (12), 1853-1883 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bagg, Harriet (2), 1860's (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bagg, J. Newton (1), 1850 circa (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Barber, Mary (14), 1852-1895, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - (Davis, Belle?) (10), 1850c.-1881 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Harrington, Julia (11), 1866-1885, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Look, Polly Loomis (5), 1850c.-1867 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Loomis family, various (5), 1858-1898 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Loomis, Achsie Ashley (9), 1852c.-1870 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Loomis, Celestia (6), 1849-1854 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Loomis, Eben J. (21), 1850-1896 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Loomis, George (18), 1848-1898 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Loomis, Joseph (14), 1848-1891 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Loomis, Mahlon (9), 1852-1881 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Loomis, Nathan (4), 1866-1871 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bagg, J. Newton
      - A-T, various (9), 1854-1903 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Bagg, Mary S. Loomis (3), 1852-1853, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bagg, Winthrop Sears
      - Loomis, Harriet E. Bagg (1), 1869 circa (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Barber family, various
      - Loomis family, various (4), 1849-1853 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Barber, Mr. and Mrs. Samuel (4), 1831-1835, undated
      - Williams, Eliza Barber (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Loomis, W.J. Barber (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Coonley, Mrs. Lydia Avery
      - Loomis, Nathan (1), 1823 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Todd, Mabel L.
    - Elwell, Mrs.
      - Bagg, Mary Loomis (1), 1854 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Gardner, Eugene C.
      - Todd, David Peck and Todd, Mabel Loomis
        General note
    - Gardner, Mrs. Lucy Barber (2), 1830, various (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Look, Mrs. Polly Loomis
      - Sprague, Susannah (2), 1871 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Loomis, Mary Sears (3), 1876-1877 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Loomis, Colette
      - Bowles, Samuel
        See: box 3, folders 97-112
      - Loomis, Eben J. (3), 1852-1860 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - ____, Mahlon (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Loomis, W.J.B. (3), 1859 circa (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Loomis, Dyer (2), 1848-1856
      - Loomis, Eben J. (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - ____, Nathan (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Loomis, Eliza
      - Gardner, Eugene C. (1), 1876 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Loomis, Colette (10), 1857-1860 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Loomis, Eben J. (24), 1853-1874 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Loomis, George (11), 1853-1884 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Loomis, Joseph (7), 1856-1883 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Loomis, Mr. and Mrs. Nathan (4), 1858-1874 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Parsons, Nellie L. (2), 1883 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Loomis, Mr. and Mrs. George (25)
      - Bagg, Mr. and Mrs. J. Newton, 1846-1886 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Loomis, George
      - Loomis, Colette (6), 1851-1855 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Loomis, Eben J. (1), 1884 circa (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Loomis, Eliza (18), 1852c.-1883 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Loomis, Mr. and Mrs. Nathan (4), 1845-1852 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Parsons, Ellen Loomis (4), 1859-1863 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Loomis, Hattie Bagg (2) (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - various, 1874c.-1915 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Loomis, Harriet Bagg
      See: Todd, Mabel Loomis Collection
    - Loomis, Joseph
      - Bagg, Mary S. (3), 1848-1883 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Foster, J.F. (7), 1887-1888 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Gardner (E.C.?)(4), 1875-1886 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Loomis, Eben J. (7), 1888-1895 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Loomis, Eliza (9), 1880-1885 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Loomis, George (18), 1876-1894 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Loomis, Harriet E. Bagg (3), 1878-1885 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - Loomis, Mahlon (13), 1856-1886 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - Loomis, Nathan (2), 1871, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 52)
      - Parsons, Ellen Loomis (5), 1893-1895 (Box 2, Folder 53)
      - Various (13), 1862-1892 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Loomis, Mahlon and Achsie
      - Bagg, Mary Sears Loomis (3), 1852-1855 (Box 2, Folder 55)
      - Loomis, Eben (3), 1859, 1885-1886 (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - ____, Joseph (Box 2, Folder 56)
      - ____, George (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Loomis, Mahlon
      - Murry, E.R. (1), 1850's (Box 2, Folder 57)
      - Loomis, Achsie Ashley (Box 2, Folder 57)
        See also: Todd, Mabel L. Collection: Correspondence
      - Wilder, John A. (1), 1853 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Loomis, Nathan
      - Burritt, E.H. (5), 1822-1838 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - Clark, Alvah (2), 1865-1876 (Box 2, Folder 60)
      - Loomis, Josiah, Jr. (4), 1840c.-1875c. (Box 2, Folder 61)
      - Loomis, Waite J. Barber (1), 1850 circa (Box 2, Folder 62)
      - Various, family (6), 1869-1875 (Box 2, Folder 63)
        See also: Todd, Mabel L. Collection: Correspondence; also see: Juvenilia: Correspondence
    - Loomis, Nathan and Loomis, Waite J. Barber
      (including 1 letter notebook)
      - Bagg, J. Newton (2), 1853-1876 (Box 2, Folder 64)
      - Loomis, Colette (7), 1857c-1861 (Box 2, Folder 65)
      - Loomis, Eben J. (7), 1851-1857 (Box 2, Folder 66)
      - Loomis, Eliza Waite (4), 1859-1874, undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
      - Loomis, George (6), 1848-1871 (Box 2, Folder 68)
      - Loomis, Joseph (4), 1854-1876 (Box 2, Folder 69)
      - Loomis, Mahlon (6), 1852-1874 (Box 2, Folder 70)
      - Barber family, various (15), 1830-1875 (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - Various (non-family) (2), 1826-1842 (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - White, Hannah (3), 1820-1839 (Box 2, Folder 72A)
    - Loomis, Waite Jenks Barber
      - Loomis, Nathan (3), 1850-1851 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Loomis, Sarah E.
      - Bagg, Mary S. Loomis (1), 1895 (Box 2, Folder 74)
        See also: Todd, Mabel Collection: Correspondence
    - Loomis family
      - various (3), 1852-1860, undated (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - McGrew, Ada Loomis
      - Loomis, Eben J. (1), 1868 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Parsons, Nellie Loomis
      - Loomis, Eben J. (1), 1857, 1884 (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - ____, Waite J. Barber (Box 2, Folder 77)
      - Bagg, Mary S. Loomis (3), 1870c.-1895 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Schober, Carrie Loomis
      - Various (Loomis family) (5), 1876-1887 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Williams, Mr. and Mrs. David
      - Loomis, Nathan and Waite J.B. (3), 1829-1858 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Unidentified
      - Bagg, Mary S. Loomis (6), 1850c.-1870c., undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
      - Loomis, George (1), 1842 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      - Loomis, Nathan (3), 1834-1837, undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
      - Loomis family (unidentified) (12), 1850c., 1864, undated (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Personal and Legal Records
    - Loomis and Barger genealogy, notebook on by Eben J. Loomis, 1863 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Biographical and genealogical notes on Loomis, Barber, Sears, Look, and Jenks families, 1850-c.1960 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Loomis family and relatives: newspaper clippings, 1895c.-1919 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - The Loomis Family in America, 1905 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Barber family deeds and writings, 1803-1830, undated (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Loomis family, various: writings and sketches by unidentified family members, 1849, 1876, undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Miscellaneous notes and writings by unidentified persons, found with Loomis papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Bagg, Mary Sears Loomis
      - Childhood sketches and writings, undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
      - Journals, 1850-1852, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 93)
      - Original writings: prose and poetry, 1850c. and undated (Box 3, Folder 94)
      - Notes, poems, sketches, in various hands, found with Mary S.L. Bagg papers, 1848, 1877, undated (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - Funeral service and obituary, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Loomis, Colette
      - Writings, notes for a bibliography, 1888-1968, undated (Box 3, Folder 97)
      - Drawings, 1853, undated (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - Diaries (6) and small notebook, 1851-1856, undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
      - Diary at Mr. Holyoke Seminary: typed copies, September 1859-March 1861 (Box 3, Folder 100)
      - "Little Willie: A Schoolroom Sketch" Springfield Republican, Circa March 1860 (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - Small booklets (3) of original poetry and prose, n.s. (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - Mss booklet of poetry, some printed copies, 1853-1856, undated (Box 3, Folder 103)
      - Poems, published, many with Mss drafts: in alphabetical order, undated (Box 4, Folder 104)
      - Poems in draft, no record of publication: alphabetical order, undated (Box 4, Folder 105)
      - Publication of poems: letter from Samuel, Bowles, Editor of Springfield Republican, Circa1858 (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - Biography of Colette Loomis, with extracts from her diary and poetry, by Mabel L. Todd
        - Handwritten Mss, Circa1924 (Box 4, Folder 107)
        - Typed copy, Circa1924 (Box 4, Folder 108)
        - Carbon of typed copy (uncorrected), Circa1924 (Box 4, Folder 109)
        - Fragments of typed copy, Circa1924 (Box 4, Folder 110)
        - Correspondence concerning publication, 1920-1924 (Box 4, Folder 111)
      - Obituary, memorial poetry, biographical information, 1861 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Loomis, Eliza Waite
      - Miscellaneous, 1876 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Loomis, Eliza W., Mary S., Joseph B.
      - Sketches, undated (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Loomis, George
      - Commonplace books, 1835-1839, undated (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - Mss. journals (broken series), 1835-1850 (Box 4, Folder 116)
      - Handwritten and typed excerpts from Mss. journals, 1835-1838 (Box 4, Folder 117)
      - Correspondence concerning printing of Journal of George Loomis of c.1835, 1904-1937 (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - "Memorandum Book, or Farm Yard Journal,", 1830-1840 (Box 4, Folder 119)
      - Original poetry and prose, Circa1840 (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - Writing: "Pioneer in Telegraphing Without Wires" (on Mahlon Loomis) New England Magazine, April 1901 (Box 4, Folder 121)
      - "A Philosopher Goes A-Journeying" American Motorist, July 1932 (using G.L. letters on trip Va.-W.Va. (Box 4, Folder 122)
      - Obituary in Parkersburg, Va. Sentinel, April 19, 1902 (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Loomis, Joseph
      - Mss. autobiographical, to 1842 and later (Box 5, Folder 124)
      - Annotated Almanacs (diary entries), 1857, 1861 (Box 5, Folder 125)
      - Diary, 1859 (Box 5, Folder 126)
      - Notebook on trip to Cape Cod with Eben J. Loomis, September 1861 (Box 5, Folder 127)
      - Mss. notebook of writings, mainly poetry, 1843-1858, undated (Box 5, Folder 128)
      - Poetry: published, 1853, 1870, undated (Box 5, Folder 129)
      - Press-book of original writings and loose drafts, 1849-1854, undated (Box 5, Folder 130)
      - Prose: published Man's Immortality, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 131)
      - Financial papers, 1863-1884 (Box 5, Folder 132)
      - Writings and papers concerning inventions, 1850, 1867, 1876-1877, n.d (Box 5, Folder 133)
      - Miscellaneous printed matter and writings of others, 1838-1888, undated (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Loomis, Rev. Josiah, Sr.
      - Will and insurance, 1838, 1857 (Box 5, Folder 135)
    - Loomis, Mahlon
      - Miscellaneous (mostly biographical material), 1854-1912, undated (Box 5, Folder 136)
      - List of Mss. available elsewhere, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 137)
    - Loomis, Nathan
      - Commonplace Book
        See: Folio 35
      - Poems by N.L., 1821-1857 (Box 5, Folder 138)
      - Writings, various, Circa1822-1865 (Box 5, Folder 139)
      - Financial and legal papers, 1827-1875 (Box 5, Folder 140)
      - Land survey: Fairfax County, Va., 1842 (Box 5, Folder 141)
      - Building of house, West Springfield, Mass., Contracts and accounts, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 142)
      - Miscellaneous, 1842, 1859-1860 (Box 5, Folder 143)
      - Obituary and biographical material, 1876, undated (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Loomis, Susanna Howes
      - Mss book of religious texts, 1804-1833 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Loomis, Waite Jenks Barber
      - Brief journal, 1841 (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Parsons, Nellie Loomis
      - Journal portion and Mss poetry, 1853, 1861, undated (Box 5, Folder 147)
      - Printed matter: biographical information on Mss elsewhere; obituary, 1886-1907 (Box 5, Folder 148)
- EBEN J. LOOMIS (1828-1912), 1828, 1845-1912; Series II; 7.25 linear feet (17 boxes)
  This series contains most of the material by and about Eben Jenks Loomis. It is divided into three sub-series:
  Correspondence
  Correspondence includes letters to and from E.J. Loomis, arranged alphabetically by the name of the correspondent. See the general note on correspondence in the Introduction to the register. Letters of a social nature addressed to Loomis and his wife jointly have been filed under her correspondence (Series III). For correspondence with publishers, see Writings below. Biographical material on correspondents is filed in Personal and Financial Records; cross-references have been made on the appropriate correspondence folders.
  Writings
  Writings is preceded by several folders of bibliographical material, followed by these categories:
  Books: published, unpublished (chronological order)
  Articles: published, unpublished (chronological order, except for unpublished articles of unknown date)
  Lectures (by date given first)
  Poetry: published, unpublished (in alphabetical order by title)
  Various short drafts and notes, mostly untitled and with no dates, are to be found at the end of the "Articles: Unpublished" section. The folders contain the following materials, when available, for each work:
  Notes for and drafts of the work
  Printed version of the work
  Correspondence with publishers
  Records of payment
  For book section: contracts, copyright, proofs, publicity and reviews
  Asterisks beside folder titles for books indicate that the book is in the collection and may be consulted. In the sections "Articles: Published" and "Poetry: Published," the symbols (WS) and (SI) on the folders refer to the item's subsequent publication in the books entitled, respectively, Wayside Sketches and Sunset Idyll.
  Personal and Financial Records
  Personal and Financial Records includes material for Mary Wilder Loomis (see her correspondence in Series III). It is preceded by biographical material on the Loomises, followed by the following groupings:
  Journals, Diaries, and Notebooks
  Financial Records
  Educational and Professional Papers of E.J. Loomis (including material on the Nautical Almanac Office)
  Miscellany (Loomis homes, Mary W. Loomis personal and household records, informations files on correspondents, etc.)
  - Correspondence
    - A, various (4), 1867-1904 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Ammidon, Philip R. (33), 1857-1880 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Ammidon, Philip R. (22), 1881-1889 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Antrobus, R.L. (1), 1891 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Avery, Susan Look (11), 1881-1910 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - B, various (16), Circa1856-1906 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Bagg, Ernest; ________, J. Newton (3), 1858,1886-1888 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Bagg, Mary S.L. (13), 1854-1896 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Bardwell, F.W. (32), 1857-1871 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Bingham, Millicent Todd.
      See: M.T. Bingham collection
    - Blossom, W.A. (5), 1858-1881 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Bowman, C.G. (4), 1876-1883 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Brinton, Grace Parsons; ________, Gretchen Chester; ________, Nellie Loomis (4), 1909-1910 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Buchanan, Reoberdean (6), 1883-1903 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Burroughs, John (3), 1877-1906 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - C, various (8), 1858-1885 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Coffin, J.H.C. (16), 1876-1885 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Cutter, H. Maria; ________, J.M.; ________, M.M. (3), 1870's-1880 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - D, various (12), 1865-1908 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Darwin, Charles (2), 1881 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Downing, A.W. (1), 1877 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - E, various (5), 1886-1894 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Eastwood, George (11), 1860-1887 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Eaton, Dr. P.H. (2), 1891, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - F, various (5), 1859-1904 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - G, various (11), 1866-1908 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Gardner, Eugene C. (13), 1863-1911 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Gray, Asa (3), 1880 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - H, various (29), 1857-1912 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Hall, Angeline (3), 1875-1888 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Heade, M.J. (42), 1882-1888 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Hill, G.W. (8), 1865-1912 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Hosmer, Alfred W. (5), 1896 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Howells, Mr. and Mrs. W.D. (3), 1886-1907 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - J, various (3), 1894, 1903-1912 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Jefferis, William M. (4), 1903 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Johnson, William Wolsey (4), 1865-1885 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - ? Jones, Elliot (2), 1876-1879 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Jones, Emmeline (2), 1880-1886 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - K, various (6), 1883-1906 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - L, various (14), 1859-1905 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Leavitt, John H. (7), 1857-1865 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Loomis, Colette (3), 1858-1860 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Loomis, Dyer (1), 1874 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Loomis, Elias (1), 1870 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - Loomis, Eliza (20), 1856-1884 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Loomis, George (29), 1858-1886 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - Loomis, Harriet E. Bagg (5), 1905-1909 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Loomis, Joseph (46), 1856-1894 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Loomis, Mahlon (21), 1856-1867 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Loomis, Mary A. Wilder (46), 1852-1865 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - ________________ (70), 1865-1869 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - ________________ (51), 1870-1874 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - ________________ (51), 1875-1878 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - ________________ (37), 1879-1887 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - ________________ (20), 1888-1891 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Loomis, Mary Sears
      See: box 1, folder 37
    - Loomis, Nathan (61), 1850-1874 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Loomis, Nellie (Ellen)
      See: box 8, folder 72
    - Loomis, Sarah E. (15), 1878-1888 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Loomis, Waite J. Barber (5), Circa1856-1859 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Loomis, William Isaacs (1), 1864 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Loomis family (2), Circa1863, undated (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - M, various (9), 1864-1903 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - McGrew, Mr. and Mrs. Ben (3), 1868-1910 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Morilleau, L. (1), 1890 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Morrill, C. (3), 1880-1881 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - N, various (1), 1890 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Nehrling, H. (3), 1889-1890 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Newcomb, Mr. and Mrs. Simon (15), 1884-1906 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - O, various (2), 1888 (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - Oliver, J.E. (8), 1856-1885 (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - P, various (10), 1886-1912 (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Packard, R.L. (3), 1895, undated (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Parsons, Mr. and Mrs. Henry C. (9), 1857-1902 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Pirter ?, George E. (3), 1878-1882 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Quarles, R.W. (5), 1878-1881 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - R, various (6), 1869-1894, undated (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Runkle, J.D. (2), 1884-1885 (Box 8, Folder 75A)
    - S, various (18), 1860-1912 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - Savary, John (11), 1881-1903, undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Schober, Carrie E. Loomis (3), 1902 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Sears, E.H. (3), 1864 (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Shaw, L.H. (6), 1859-1865 (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Shoemaker, W.L. (4), 1875-1885 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Siddons, J.H. (10), 1878-1886, undated (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Smithsonian Institution (8), 1855-1891 (Box 8, Folder 83)
    - Sprague, Charles (3), 1861-1864 (Box 8, Folder 84)
    - Sturdy, E.W. (3), 1883-1884 (Box 8, Folder 85)
    - Sumner, Charles (3), 1865-1871, undated (Box 8, Folder 86)
    - T, various (9), 1859-1904 (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Thatcher, George A. (6), 1887-1892 (Box 8, Folder 88)
    - Thomas, Chauncey (9), 1882-1889 (Box 8, Folder 89)
    - Thoreau, Henry D. (4), 1853-1858 (Box 8, Folder 90)
    - Thoreau, Maria (2), 1881 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Thoreau, sophia (1), 1871 (Box 8, Folder 91)
    - Todd, David P.
      See: Todd, David P. Collection: Correspondence
    - Todd, Mabel L.
      See: Todd, Mabel L. Collection: Correspondence
    - Twiss, Stephen P. (40), 1860-1888 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - U-V, various (4), 1867-1910 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - Van Vleck, J.M. (14), 1865-1868?,[1970] (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - w-[x-Y-Z] (14), 1857-1903 (Box 8A, Folder 95)
    - Ware, Edward K. (5), 1857-1860 (Box 8A, Folder 96)
    - Watson, Sereno (2), 1891 (Box 8A, Folder 97)
    - Whiting, Sarah F. (2), 1906 (Box 8A, Folder 98)
    - Whitman, Walt (2), 1882, undated (Box 8A, Folder 99)
    - Wilder, Constance Perley; ________, Charles B.; ________, Charles T.; ________, Esther (6), 1866-1900 (Box 8A, Folder 100)